Guide to the John Lowenthal Papers TAM.190
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subject Files, 1942-2003; 81036
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Fariello, Griffin, 1996-2001; cuid8831; 81137 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Feinstein, Gussie, 1978-1980; cuid8832; 81136 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Frank, Victor Reno, 1977, 1979; cuid8833; 81135 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Funding/Grants, 1977; cuid8834; 81134 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1970s; cuid8835; 81133 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Handwritten Notes, re:, 2002; cuid8836; 81132 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Herbert, F. Edward, 1976-1981; cuid8837; 81131 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: HUAC, 1976; cuid8838; 81130 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Inquiries, 1994-2000; cuid8839; 81129 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Ladd, Helen, 1977, 1979; cuid8840; 81128 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Lamb, Edward, 1976, 1979; cuid8841; 81127 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Levin, Alvin, 1979; cuid8842; 81126 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Lindau, Alfred M., 1977; cuid8843; 81125 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Media Study, Buffalo, 1981-1982; cuid8844; 81124 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Mischel, Larry, 1977, 1979; cuid8845; 81123 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Murtaugh, Edward S., 1977, 1979; cuid8846; 81122 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Newsreels, undated, 1976-1977, 1983; cuid8847; 81121 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Nixon, Richard, 1976-1977; cuid8848; 81120 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Outtakes, 1970-1999; cuid8849; 81119 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Photographs, Search for, 1994; cuid8850; 81118 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Promotions/Publicity/Distribution, International, 1980-1994; cuid8851; 81117 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Promotions/Publicity, National, undated, 1979-1982; cuid8852; 81116 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Releases, 1977-1979; cuid8853; 81115 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Schmitt, Joseph, 1977; cuid8854; 81114 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Script Additions, 2002; cuid8855; 81113 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Script Annotations, 1979; cuid8856; 81112 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Script Changes, 1983; cuid8857; 81111 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Shapero, Harold, 1977, 1984; cuid8858; 81110 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Shaw, Vincent, 1978; cuid8859; 81109 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Silk, Lawrence, 1977; cuid8860; 81108 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Smith, John Chabot, undated, 1976; cuid8861; 81107 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Sound/Tape Reports, 1976-1977; cuid8862; 81106 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Spencer, Thomas G., 1949, 1977; cuid8863; 81105 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Strauss, Robert S., Aug 1992; cuid8864; 81104 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Stock Footage, undated, 1970s; cuid8865; 81103 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Stripling, Robert, 1977, 1980; cuid8866; 81102 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Sullivan, William, 1975, 1977; cuid8867; 81101 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Taylor, Duncan Norton, undated, 1977; cuid8868; 81100 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Timeline, undated; cuid8869; 81099 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Transcript, 1979; cuid8870; 81098 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Typescript, p. 1-100, 1979; cuid8871; 81097 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Typescript, p. 101-214, 1979; cuid8872; 81096 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Tytell Typewriter, 1976-1977; cuid8873; 81095 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: University of California, Berkeley, Pacific Film Archive, undated; cuid8874; 81094 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: von Werner, Robert, 1977; cuid8875; 81093 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Witt, Nathan, 1976-1977, 1982; cuid8876; 81092 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Zablodowsky, David, 1977, 1981; cuid8877; 81091 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Turner, Kay: Correspondence, 1996; cuid8878; 81090 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Tytell, Martin: "The $7,500 Typewriter I Built for Alger Hiss" (True Magazine), Aug 1952; cuid8879; 81089 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - United Nations: Notes and Typescript, undated, 1965; cuid8880; 81088 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - United States Court of Appeals: USA v. Morton Sobell, 1963; cuid8881; 81087 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - USA v. Alger Hiss: The Film Fund, 1976-1978; cuid8882; 81086 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - USA v. Alger Hiss: National Endowment for the Humanities, 1976-1978; cuid8883; 81085 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - USA v. Alger Hiss: The Television Laboratory, 1976-1978; cuid8884; 81084 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - United States Department of Agriculture: Agricultural Adjustment Administration, 1935; cuid8885; 81083 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Van der Heuvel, Katrina, 1992-1995; cuid8886; 81082 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander v. Frank Cass and Co., 2001-2002; cuid8887; 81081 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander v. Frank Cass and Co., 2003; cuid8888; 81080 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Venona, 1990s; cuid8889; 81079 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Venona: "Ales" Awarded Soviet Decoration, 1953, 2000; cuid8890; 81078 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Venona Article: Correspondence, 1999; cuid8891; 81077 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Venona Article: Draft, 1999-2000; cuid8892; 81076 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Venona Article: Mailing Lists and Public Relations, 2000-2002; cuid8893; 81075 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Venona Article: Notes, re:, 2000-2002; cuid8894; 81074 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Venona Article: Referees, 2002; cuid8895; 81073 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Venona Article: Responses, 2002-2003; cuid8896; 81072 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Venona: Bykov, Boris, 1996-1999; cuid8897; 81071 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Venona Conference, Oct 3, 1996-Oct 4, 1996; cuid8898; 81070 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Vinnedge, Harlan: Correspondence, 1973-1974; cuid8899; 81069 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Vinnedge, Harlan: "A Second Look at the Hiss Case," Typescript, undated; cuid8900; 81068 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Visson, Lynn: Handwritten Notes, re:, Dec 1992; cuid8901; 81067 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Von Mehren, Robert: Correspondence, 1975, 1993; cuid8902; 81066 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Vyshinsky, Andrei Y: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1996, 2002; cuid8903; 81065 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - W. H. Lowdermilk and Company: HUAC Reprints, re:, May 1962; cuid8904; 81064 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Wadleigh, Henry Julian, 1948-1950, 1977, 1994; cuid8905; 81063 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Washington Post: Correspondence, 1992-1993; cuid8906; 81062 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Website: The Alger Hiss Story, 2000-2001; cuid8907; 81061 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Website: The Alger Hiss Story, Zip Disc, Nov 11, 2000; cuid8908; 81060 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Weinstein, Allen, 1970-1999; cuid8909; 81059 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Weinstein, Allen: The Haunted Wood, re:, 1990s; cuid8910; 81058 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Weinstein, Allen: Perjury, Re:, 1970s; cuid8911; 81057 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Welles, Summer: Handwritten Notes, re:, Feb 12, 1949; cuid8912; 81056 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Were Oppenheimer, Sobell and Hiss Spies?: Typescript and Notes, 1994; cuid8913; 81055 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, undated, 1952, 1976-1999; cuid8914; 81054 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: American Playhouse, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case", 1984; cuid8915; 81053 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Alger Hiss Project," First of Three Films, Typescript, undated; cuid8916; 81052 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Part 1 Accusation," Revised Draft, undated; cuid8917; 81051 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Part 2 Confession," First Draft, undated; cuid8918; 81050 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Parts 1 and 2," Revisions, Jul 1983; cuid8919; 81049 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Part 3 Investigation," Revisions, 1983; cuid8920; 81048 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: "The Trials of Alger Hiss," Treatment, 1980; cuid8921; 81047 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Why Ales Cannot Be Alger Hiss (JL): Typescript, 1996; cuid8922; 81046 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Wiener, John: "Compromised Positions" (The Nation), Jan 1993-Feb 1993; cuid8923; 81045 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Wiener, John: Re: "Pumpkin Papers", 1990, 1996-1998; cuid8924; 81044 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Wines, Michael: Correspondence, 1992; cuid8925; 81043 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Wood, Sally: Correspondence, Feb 3, 1950; cuid8926; 81042 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center for Cold War History: Handwritten Notes re: Hiss, 1992-1993, 2003; cuid8927; 81041 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Worth, Joan: Correspondence, 1993; cuid8928; 81040 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Wright, Charles A.: Writings, 1952, 1973, 2000; cuid8929; 81039 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Younger, Irving: Re: Hiss, 1970s; cuid8930; 81038 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Zubok, Vladislav, 1993; cuid8931; 81037 (Box 23, Folder 33)
- Series III: Alger Hiss Production Files, 1938-1991; 514485
  - Associated Press Photograph Description, undated; cuid8932; 525371 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, undated; cuid8933; 525369 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons (Oversize), undated; cuid8934; 525375 (Box OS003, Folder 1)
  - Chambers, Esther, 1948-1962; cuid8935; 514506 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1948-1950; cuid8936; 514509 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Chambers at Farm, 1949-1953; cuid8937; 514507 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Chambers' Farm and Pumpkins, 1948, undated; cuid8938; 514505 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Chambers with Stripling, Nixon and Bentley, 1951; cuid8939; 514508 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Chambers at HUAC, undated; cuid8940; 525352 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Collins and Hiss, undated; cuid8941; 514494 (Box 34, Folder data_value_missing_59fe5b69f198012634f73edb14ed21fc)
  - Daily News (Negatives and Photocopies), 1934-1961; cuid8942; 514493 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - [Damaged Negatives], undated; cuid8943; 525373 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Documents, 1938-1957; cuid8944; 525354 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Donald Hiss (Includes Alger Hiss), 1948; cuid8945; 514500 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Alger: LIFE (Photocopies), undated; cuid8946; 514491 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Hiss: Alone, 1948-1950; cuid8947; 525357 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Hiss: at HUAC, 1948-1961; cuid8948; 525355 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Hiss: NYE Committee / San Francisco Conference / YALTA, 1945; cuid8949; 525353 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Hiss: Personal - Familly and Friends, 1951-1975; cuid8950; 525362 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Hiss: Portraits, undated; cuid8951; 525364 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Hiss: Prison, Mug Shot, Handcuffs, Post-Prison Press Conferences, 1946-1956; cuid8952; 514487 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Hiss: Stationary Office, Massachussets Bar, 1967-1976; cuid8953; 514499 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Hiss: with Priscilla, Tony Alone, 1949-1959; cuid8954; 514498 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - HUAC: Long Shots, CU Stripling, Mundt, Thomas Guarding Pumpkin Papers, 1943-1948; cuid8955; 514497 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Index of Tabbed Photographs, undated; cuid8956; 525370 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Judges Kaufman and Goddard, 1949-1950; cuid8957; 514501 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Juries: 1st and 2nd, 1948-1950; cuid8958; 514502 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Lawyers: Corss, Stryker, Rosenwald, McLean, Shapero, 1949, undated; cuid8959; 514503 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Lowenthal, John Portraits and Contract Sheets, 1980-1981; undated; cuid8960; 525367 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Great Depression), undated; cuid8961; 525368 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Includes Paul Robeson, Communities, Spanish Civil War), 1948-1962; cuid8962; 525358 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Dupicate and Promotional Photographs, 1980-1991, undated; cuid8963; 514496 (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Promotional Photographs, 1948-1951; cuid8964; 525365 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - Mundt / "Hiss Guilty" Headline, 1948; cuid8965; 525356 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - Murphy, Thomas F., 1950-1951; cuid8966; 525359 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1949-1977; cuid8967; 525372 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - Nixon, 1948-1955; cuid8968; 525360 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - Original Photographs, undated; cuid8969; 525363 (Box 34, Folder 37)
  - Oversize, 1953-1979; undated; cuid8970; 525374 (Box OS003, Folder 2)
  - Personalities, 1931-1969; cuid8971; 514504 (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - Photos Used in Final Cut, 1948-1952; cuid8972; 514495 (Box 34, Folder 39)
  - Press Stills, 1955-1970; undated; cuid8973; 514486 (Box 34, Folder 40)
  - Pulled for Possible Promotion (Hiss on Trial), 1948-1955; cuid8974; 514492 (Box 34, Folder 41)
  - Shoot Rehearsed Movement (Whittaker Chambers, Alger Hiss, Henry Julian Wadleigh), 1943-1951; cuid8975; 514489 (Box 34, Folder 42)
  - Shoot - Straight (Whittaker Chambers, Robert Stripling, Sumner Welles), 1948-1950; cuid8976; 514490 (Box 34, Folder 43)
  - Stripling and Wheeler, 1944-1948; cuid8977; 525361 (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Swish to Left on Mach (Oliver Edmond Clubb and Whittaker Chambers), 1951, undated; cuid8978; 514488 (Box 34, Folder data_value_missing_cb7413ad1b839effcf712f43d3b38864)
- Series IV: Addendum, 1949-1993; 290811
  This unprocessed box (1 linear foot) of material is not available for research, pending its reorganization, description, and completion of basic preservation measures.
  - Agnese Nelms Haury Trust / Emil W. Haury Graduate Fellowship Fund, 1991-1992; cuid8979; 336939 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Gray Panthers [2 posters], 1982; undated; cuid8980; 478923 (Box MSXOS002, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, Anne [Professor]: Correspondence, 1976, 1979; cuid8981; 336940 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Lowenthal, John: Correspondence, 1954-1960; cuid8982; 336941 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Lowenthal, John: Correspondence, 1971-1993; cuid8983; 336942 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Lowenthal, John: Letter to "Mother", undated; cuid8984; 336943 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Lowenthal, John: Letter to Mr. and Mrs. John Wolf [from Paris], Aug 15, 1949; cuid8985; 336944 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Lowenthal, John: Letters to Lowenthal Family [from Paris], Jul 1949-Sep 1949; cuid8986; 336945 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "More on Whittaker Chambers and NYPL" (Research Libraries Bulletin; vol. 5, no. 3), 1993; cuid8987; 336946 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - "The Trials of Algiers Hiss" (92nd St Y) [poster], [1980]; cuid8988; 487335 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 14)
  - The Trials of Alger Hiss [Film brochure], c. 1980; cuid8989; 336947 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "The Trials of Algiers Hiss"(London Film Festival) [poster], 1980; cuid8990; 478922 (Box MSXOS002, Folder 1)
  - "The Trials of Algiers Hiss" [poster], [1980]; cuid8991; 487334 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 14)
  - U.S. Troops Out Now [poster], undated; cuid8992; 478924 (Box MSXOS002, Folder 1)
  - "Vindication for Alger Hiss" (Rochester Chronicle), Nov 18, 1992; cuid8993; 336948 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - David Levine caricature of Alger Hiss and Richard Nixon, 1975; cuid8995 (Box Shared Tamiment 011, Folder 2)
- Series V: Unprocessed Materials, Undated; 372617
  - "Libyan Technical Assistance - "International Conciliation", 1957-05-02; cuid8996 (Reel 1, Reel cuid8996, E-records tamwag_tam190, E-records cuid8996)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: 1/4" open reel audio, Duration: 30 min.
  - Film, "Chip Lockwood, et al", 1965-01-29; cuid8997 (Box Shared Tamiment 013, Reel 2, Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Unmarked film, undated; cuid8998 (Box Shared Tamiment 013, Reel 3)
  - Candid portrait, undated; cuid8999 (Box Shared Tamiment 011, Folder 14)